in theory ssrf is a really simple
vulnerability class you can make
requests to arbitrary locations but in
practice there are so many questions
what functionalities are actually
vulnerable do you really need all the
crazy ssrf payloads we've all seen and
finally how are people proving the
impact of ssrf's in real life I wanted
to know answers to this question so I
went on the internet and I extracted 361
back Bounty reports then filtered them
out and categorize them to learn how are
people actually making money with
accessorize I shared the whole case
study along with the database of those
reports in bbru premium but in this
video I will show you what
functionalities are most likely to be
vulnerable to assessor apps enjoy
turns out that the functionality most
likely to be vulnerable to ssrfs is
different kinds of upload by URL
functionality in many cases this meant
uploading avatars or something with with
avatars or otherwise images
but what I want you to note is that many
of these ssrfs are actually blind not
many of these functionalities gave the
attacker the ability to read the
response which is crucial if we want to
get the highest impact even though
they're well the highest Bounty was
fifteen thousand and it was a report
from 2021 and it was a blind ssrf but it
was escalated to an rce using the Gopher
protocol and radish if I remember
correctly
the next
highest Bounty was 12 000 and it's a
report that I also covered on my channel
it's an ssrf in grafana where Rhino
hater combined I think three open
redirects to get this vulnerability
otherwise we have quite a lot of 500
payouts or lower payouts uh often due to
the fact that this only allowed a blind
exploitation
the next group of vulnerabilities is
uploaded by upload functionality it's a
bit different because in that case the
app really allowed us to input a URL to
to import something from the remote
resource and it's quite obvious to test
for ssrfs I think this is the first
functionality that I think about when I
think about accessor apps in file upload
however we are uploading a file from our
local computer and the processing of the
file actually causes the server to make
a request where it shouldn't make the
request there were 17 reports like this
but out of them six were ffmpeg CV is
it's a video format where it was
possible to make requests to arbitrary
locations or even read local files
and
in each case remember that this is a
sample size of 124 reports because very
small percentage of all back vanity
reports are actually disclosed so if we
have six reports here it probably means
there are tens or hundreds of reports
that are not discussed about the same
bug so there were six occurrences of
this I think there are they are mostly
from 17 2016.
I don't know what is the freshest one
2020 one payout
so I if I'm afraid that
it won't really work also we have seven
x axis in in this group uh majority of
them were in SVG files where you could
trigger the server into making a
requests
into arbitrary locations and with this
group of assassraps the file upload SSR
apps or file processing ssrefs note how
many of these allow using file protocol
it makes exploitation that much easier
because you can just read a local file
on the server and I would assume that
some of similar reports to what I have
here
are reported and maybe even disclosed
but aren't reported as ssrfs but as
arbitrary file reads which
I would say in this context doesn't
really make a difference
the next one is different
functionalities in regards to headless
browsers so the server takes an HTML
from the user or some input from the
user and renders the HTML on the back
end usually to create a PDF or generate
an image
there were nine reports like this and I
think this is one of the promising
functionalities because I feel that more
and more servers are utilizing headless
browsers for for different tasks so
that's definitely
something to to look out for in
seven out of these nine cases there was
iframe SRC payload used
and almost all of these ssrfs allowed
full read of the response which also
made the impact greater then the next
functionality only one report last was
web hooks or some kind of checking
server status
for example
let's take this report from
Google where
there was just a functionality to check
if your Google Cloud Server is up and
running or not it was called uptime
checks
and in this case there was actually no
filtering because that response wasn't
directly shown to the attacker
so I think the developers didn't predict
this can be used for ssrfs but the
hunter was able to exfiltrate the data
of the response by using reg axis and a
blind exfiltration method very similar
to a blind SQL injection I also covered
this video on this back Bounty report in
a video on my channel and I also created
a Hands-On lab where you can try
reproducing this it was 31 000 ssrf
which makes it the highest paying one
from from this group
and I think this
um this functionality is also quite
obvious to test for ssrefs which on one
side is good but on the other side it's
probably more and more likely that
developers are also aware of this and uh
ssrfs in these obvious places will be
less and less common also out of these
uh these Aid reports
that I have here the redirect was used
in five of them which is quite a lot so
you didn't need any complex payloads
octal encoding nothing like this all you
needed to do was to use a redirect and
the server didn't did check the location
of the original URL but not when
following the redirect
let's go next with actually the same
amount of reports there is uh different
processing functionality where
the server was making a request on the
back end uh probably to some
microservice or to some external API and
it was possible to to trick the server
into making a request into
a location controlled by the attacker
note how many of these reports are
relatively recent we have you know 2020
20 21 2022 if you compare this with with
this previous bugs it seems like it's
it's a quite a new vector and I think
this is one of the more promising
um
results of this case study because
probably
it's very trendy to to have more complex
backend functionality on the servers
instead of the monolith we have like
microservices different apis external
apis as well so in many cases the server
will make requests using our input and
in some cases we can utilize this to
create ssrfs in this case often it was
enough to just send a valid parameter to
the user in the full version of this
case study there is also a list of the
parameters with amount of occurrences
and it's no surprise that the URL
parameter was the most common one I'm
stepping next to the group that I've
called security mechanism or a library
back
this means that the bug was found not in
a particular application with a
particular impact
but it was in software which anyone can
install in their own
infrastructure or use as a library
out of these seven reports there are
actually three that were sent to stripe
about smoke screen smoke screen is one
of the targets that I challenged when
doing 100 hour challenge on stripe
and I found a bypass of the denial is
there and it's one of these seven
reports and then two other people found
yet another bypasses on the same
functionality
and I saw on Twitter someone mentioning
yet another three years bypass I don't
know yet what it is
um but if you want to see that video
about my initial bypass uh then check
out the the card in your or top right
hand corner
and I like bugs like this because for
one
the case study also showed how many
reports were were blind were report the
ssrf didn't allow the attacker to read
the response and in this case it's very
hard to show the impact sometimes you
can do a part scan but often you can't
really do much and you don't know if
this is impactful or not if it's an
immature program they they won't check
this for you and
probably considering that most reports
were blind from these disclose disclosed
ones
I'm sure that there are many many more
blind ssrfs out there that are just not
reported because it's hard to show the
impact of them or they have no impact
because it is also possible
so on the other hand
when you're looking for bugs in in
libraries or security mechanisms we
don't have to care about this because
the the library is like abstract so they
they don't know what's in their clients
infrastructure so if there is a bypass
it's a clear impact and you don't have
to actually scan the target's
infrastructure which can also get you in
trouble in some cases
then with the same amount of reports we
have file storage integration and it
can be can seem as similar vulnerability
to the file uploads category but it's
actually completely different in file
uploads category we uploaded the file
from our local computer
and the server was processing these
files in file storage integration
we upload a normal file to the server
and it tries to store it on Amazon S3 or
on Google Drive or something like this
for example very recently I covered this
great blog post
about the ssrf in Dropbox
it's it used a very clever trick
and
it's basically this kind of bug the
server tried to fetch something from
Google Drive but that attacker was able
to trick the server into making a
request
into the into another house basically
giving him the full read as I said as we
can see here there were also a few
Amazon Integrations
and things like that
and I also think this category might be
growing in in future years because also
seems like many applications these days
tend to use external Solutions instead
of developing something themselves
that's why cloud is becoming more
popular
so I would also guess this is the
direction
next we have a group called Centric
integration and I was quite surprised
because I did not know about about this
attack in fact I still don't know
exactly how this how this attack works I
didn't really dig deep but the fact that
there were four reports here shows that
it was a big case these reports are from
2018 and 19 so
I would assume they they no longer work
but uh it seems to have been a big case
a Sentry is I for some kind of
um analytics I think report reporting
CSP errors also works with with Sentry
and there was some kind of
misconfiguration there
and probably you won't find it this one
in 2022 but maybe it's a good idea for a
research to try to find a similar bug
in currently used solutions for that and
maybe you can try to turn it into a bug
that you can report too many many
programs um all of these four were blind
which reduced the impact but
um one guy got three and a half thousand
for this so
it was a good a good Buck next we stuck
to the reports that only have two
occurrences in these disclosed ones
there were two reports where simply the
server made a request to the target from
the host header
which in this case
it actually uh it was in gitlab in 2019
for a four thousand dollars payout so
also a good bug
with a step step next next we have a
class that I called email configuration
and it was about the ability to control
the email domains
um I think one of these was signing up
with your own your own email domain in
the server
made the request to to your server
um one of this is in great blog post by
donut where I think three or four ssrfs
in in one blog post uh the other one was
this one Blacklist bypass for mail
account addition addition so quite a
specific
functionality and it's one of the very
few reports uh when I saw
this kind of payloads so
basically what we all know from from
different ssrf cheat sheets this is
actually I think the only the only one
when I see when I saw something like
this like uh 32-bit hex conversion and
things like that usually much simpler
things worked like IPv6 and even in this
case we can see that he just outlined
all the things that worked
so if you if you want it probably
one of these would be enough
let's go next uh to actually the last
functionality that I
uh that I have prepared only one report
about the first request line and I when
doing this case study I initially uh
created you know very detailed labels
and categories but the longer I got into
starting these reports um the better I
knew which one are too specific which
ones are to Broad
and I tried to even after the second
round of categorizing find out the ones
with like one cut with one category in
merge categories with each other but I
made an exception for for this one first
because
um literally I think in the last issue
of uh of bbr Premium I wrote about this
Behavior about proxing requests using
the first line and why it works
because I was not doing it for ssrf
study I was for some reason reading an
RFC and I saw that this is uh like the
RFC compliant
behavior and also this report was six
and a half thousand dollars and it is
relatively fresh because it spent 2020
that's why I I made an exception and uh
made a category for a single report
these are all the functionalities that I
labeled using my case study I hope this
will help you find more accessor apps if
you are interested in the full version
of this case study you can find out
they're the list of vulnerable
parameters you can see which Pilots
actually worked in real life which
bypasses where necessary
how many assets were blind and also how
people were showing impacts of of ssrfs
and also my conclusions uh after doing
this hawakai study even though I
mentioned some of my conclusions in this
video
and also I shared the whole database
with 315 reports so you can just filter
them yourself find out what's
interesting for you I only did this guy
study on those reports with a bounty and
there were 124 of them
but in the database there are all 315
reports
it's available on bbre premium platform
I encourage you to join and I guarantee
that you won't regret this you will get
instant access to the whole
Archive of over 200 articles from the
past year from bbr premium and also
every two weeks you will receive access
to the new ones it only costs ten
dollars
on my blog I also wrote about how I
created this case study and there is no
rocket science only sometime invested so
if you can't or don't want to spend 10
bucks on PBR or premium access feel free
to repeat the study using the steps from
my blog post and if you want to join go
to bbrew.dev premium for now thank you
for watching and goodbye